now that we have completed the task of
data conversion of course it's
interesting to see that related quick
process to do that we will use 3D Slicer
application that we installed in
the setup step of this tutorial so I'm
going to launch the 3D Slicer
application and i'm going to use the
dicom browser to import the data set
that we have just created so i'm going
to point it to this directory and this
will import both the source dicom images
and the segmentation represented as dicom
into my local dicom database so now
if you look at the list i have just one
patient this patient has one study and
the study consists of two series one is
the mr imaging series that we've been
segmenting earlier and another one is the
result of segmentation that we produced
so i'm going to select the segmentation
result and click load button so now you
can see this message which basically
tells you that your segmentation
was done on this MRI series
they want to load the image and of
course it makes sense because in this
doesn't help to look at segmentation
without the context so i'm going to
click proceed and now you can see that
both the segmentation and the image that
I was a segmenting are loaded into 3D
slicer
so now i can you follow the capabilities
of the slicer to work with this data and
as you can see the color is preserved
the spatial location is preserved and if
i go to the segment editor module and
mouse over this region i can see that
the information about what this
segmentation is is also preserve they
can see that it's an anatomical
structure and specifically brain
ventricle
next what I'm going to do is to load
another dataset which you can also
download if you follow the links in the
tutorial I downloaded this data set
from from the QIN collection you
can learn more about this data set if
you go to this page and if you follow
and read this paper so i'm going to
import this data set that is including
series of pet image acquisition it
includes segmentations of the primary
tumor and various on affected lymph
nodes
it also includes the measurements that
were done over the segment structures so
all of this is represented using dicom
and now is being imported into my local
database local.com database this takes a
bit longer because this is a large
larger series
ok so again i have this new patient i
have one study for this patient and you
can see that this study consists of a
pet series of consists a ct Series
something else structured report and
various segmentations so what I'm
going to do is select the structured
report and click the load button now
remember that as part of the setup
installed the quantitative reporting
extension and that's the extension of
3D Slicer that can make sense out of
this data and pull of the dependences
alongside with a structured report into
the main application now that this
process is completed you can see that
the pet series after applying the
standardized uptake very correction has
been loaded and you can see also the
overlay of the segmentations multiple
structures that were segmented for for
this patient
next I'm going to go to the quantitative
reporting extension select the loaded a
data set here and enable crosshair so
now what I can do is go over the
structures that were cemented this
particular patient I can automatically
scroll to the location of the structure
of course I can also see it in 3d
and you can also see that I have various
types of measurements calculated over
this segmentation so I know what is a
min signal over the region of interest
what is the distribution of the pixel
intensities and so forth all this data
measurements segmentations images were
loaded from dicom and all of them are
accompanied by the metadata which is
critical for meaningful analysis of this
data so for example for the segmentation
results
I know what structure is segmented by
using SNOMED terminology and for the
measurements I know what the quantities
and units assigned to these measurements